# Alka Singh

Salesforce Senior Business Analyst Certified Salesforce Admin/Sales Cloud Consultant parasharalka@gmail.com
<a href="mailto:state-of-separates">mailto:state-of-separates</a>
<a href="mailto:state-of-separates">state-of-separates</a>
<a href="m

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Sales Cloud and Service Cloud solution design.
- Documentation (BRD/FSD/UML)
- Salesforce.com Configuration & Administration
- Agile and Waterfall methodologies
- Data migration
- SCRUM with JIRA
- SQL workbench
- Quality Assurance and User Acceptance Testing
- Change/Release management
- CPQ theoretical knowledge

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- Salesforce ADM 201
- Sales Cloud Consultant

# **AWARDS & HONOURS**

- Star Performer award
- Star Team Award
- National Creativity
   Olympiad Winner

### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech in Electrical and Electronics Engineering SRM University, India - 2009 CGPA: 9.3/10

#### **PROFILE**

A senior Salesforce business analyst with certifications in Salesforce administration and Sales cloud having experience in business process modelling, system design documentation, release management and user acceptance testing. Expert in clarifying business requirements, performing gap analysis, project management and designing business processes improvements.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

HR Mobility Application, Belgium

Senior Business Analyst, Jul 2017-Present

- Defined the business requirement document of the application and performed GAP analysis in collaboration with the client.
- Led the design of the application on Force.com platform.
- Responsible for communication and management of development, testing and release of the application.
- Conducted design review and knowledge transfer sessions for the stakeholders.
- As a scrum master and program manager on the team, managed the JIRA board by creating and maintaining JIRA stories and actively tracking them to closure through the sprints.
- Test Execution & Defect Management Responsible for defect tracking of self & team

Auto Installation process for GPS devices, India

Business Analyst Jan 2017-Jun 2017

- Analyzed the business requirements to define the functional specifications.
- Managed the development team to integrate salesforce and an external REST API for vehicle identification number (VIN).
- Refreshed partial and full copy sandboxes at regular intervals after major releases.
- Worked closely with the QA automation team to ensure full coverage of test scenarios for environment stability and also release management of new features.
- Responsible for daily status reporting to management on test execution and defect resolution

Patient Relationship Management Application, India

Business Analyst Jan 2016 - Dec 2016

• Examined the functional specifications to outline the multiple phases of the project.

- Translated business requirements into technical processes and system solutions.
- Designed a quick prototype using visual force pages and salesforce trigger with minimal features to collect user feedback.

# Financial trading platform, Germany

IT Analyst

Sep 2013 - Dec 2015

- Created functional and technical design documents using flowcharts and UML diagrams.
- Developed a java web application to allow pre and post trading activities on the exchange.
- Provided production support and end user training.

Cargo load calculation in flight reservation system, India

Software Developer Jun 2010 - Aug 2013

- Designed the database schema using UML diagrams.
- Developed web application for cargo and passenger load calculation during flight tickets reservation.